(upbeat music)
- [Instructor] In the final part of this demonstration
about the context API, we're going to complete
the app refactoring with useContext,
and the goal for this challenge is to manage the state
with one single source of truth only.
So for that, we're going to call useContext
from every component, just like we did
for the app component, where we can manage
and access this state, the global state,
from one single source of truth.
As a quick reminder, useContext is a hook provided
by the React API that allows to consume data
from a context object.
So you see that we pass a context object as a perimeter,
then it returns the current value of the global state,
so we're going to do the same for every component.
The goal is to allow every component to subscribe
to the context changes so we no longer need to pass data
by using the props.
We're going to eliminate all of this one after another.
Let's begin with the form components.
We're going to update and actually allow to,
first we're going to do just like we did for the app component.
We're going to import first useContext
and add it to the scope.
And I'm going to need also to access the context objects
to pass it as a parameter.
And here as well, I'm going to copy from the app component.
It's going to be the same setting,
so I'm going to copy those two lines and add it to the form.
And now I'm going to be able to start the refactoring,
because now we can access, instead of reading the state
from the props, I'm going to remove values and instead read
from the state, the global state, like this.
And same for those two functions,
the guess and the generateRandomValues.
What we're going to do is actually move those two functions
and move it to the form, because anything related
to the form should be actually handled
and managed inside the form components.
So I'm just going to update here the name,
it's going to be generated and then guess, like this,
and we're going to keep the same for the rest,
and I think like now we no longer need this.
And for the onChange also, we're going to remove it.
We're going to update and allow to handle this
directly from the form, so I'm going to take all of this,
and inside the form, we are going to track the value
which is entered by the user this way.
But that's going to be actually e.target.value, right here.
We are going to get e and then e.target.value, like so.
And for the ref, because now instead of forwarding the ref,
so we're not going to proceed this way,
I'm going to remove all of this.
Instead, we're going to call useRef from here, so we can access
one node, and that's going to be const ref and useRef.
And I think we are almost done for this part,
so let's go back so I don't need to import that anymore,
and we have one extra trailing closing parenthesis
that is right here, so we're going to update,
and then I think we're good to go right here.
So we are just going to now update,
because we no longer need all these props,
and we're going to do the same for the component result.
Here as well, we want to be able to manage this state
by reading the state from one single source of truth,
so let's do the same.
We're going to also import,
inside the result components, useContext.
We also need to access the context objects.
And here as well, I'm going to copy those two lines,
so we can, from now on, access the state from the context.
So we just need to update because, instead of reading
from the props, I'm going to remove this, delete,
and allow to read from the global state now.
That's going to be state.result and now state.input.
Here as well, it's going to be state.result.
And we don't need to dispatch any actions
from this component, so I'm going to just keep the state
to give access to the state object.
And for the rest, it's going to be fine.
And there is one left, so let's just remove
just the props now, and we have one component left,
which is the score, so let's remove this,
because instead of passing this as a prop,
we're going to also allow to also read the state
from the global state from one single source of truth,
the same implementation.
So we're going to call useContext,
also access the context object.
We're going to copy those two lines,
and that's the same as for the result component.
We just need to read from the state object,
so no need to access the dispatch function,
and now I'm going to remove the prop.
And I think we are good to go.
I'm just going to make sure that this is up and running.
Now, inside the app component,
we can remove the code that is no longer necessary,
so that's going to be from line 16 all the way to 47,
like this, and let's remove also these functions,
because now we are, so, every component is responsible
for handling their functionalities,
and we no longer need that as well.
And now the app component is going to be much lighter.
So this is one component, one single responsibility.
This allows to separate the business logic
from the presentation.
So let's try that.
So now the app is up and running,
so we are going to be able to make one quick test
to see if this is working properly.
So we have 27 and 48.
Let's see if we can have a good match.
Perfect. So this is working perfect.
Good job for completing the challenge!
By centralizing state managements with one single
source of truth, you can help ensure that all companies
have access to the most up to date data.
Using the context API helps avoid the common issue
of props drilling.
It helps improve data consistency and eliminates
potential conflicts that could arise from scattered
and duplicated states.
Overall, the context API is a powerful tool
that helps simplify data sharing, reduce code complexity,
improve performance, and it helps make the state management
easier to maintain in your React application.